Hi guys, I'm Chambo. I went into
finance, worked there for 3 years, and
here we are six [music] years later with
the 2 million followers. The most
interesting ones were probably
>> You filmed that?
>> I beat 60 professional chefs. Let's go.
I would buy a bottle of soju. I would
chug it in one shot [music]
and hash. Koreans can be perfectionists.
Don't worry about your accent. [music]
Spit it out.
>> Go for it.
>> That's it.
>> All right.
>> Crack open a beer.
>> Oh yeah. Cheers.
>> Cheers.
[sighs]
>> Oh, that's good. Amazing. Hi guys, I'm
Chambo. I am originally from Australia
and I am working as a content creator
here in Korea.
I've been in Korea for 6 years now and I
was also here for one year as an
exchange student at Soul National back
in 2013. So, a total of seven years.
>> You used to work in finance, you said,
right? Yes. How did you go from finance
to content creation?
>> Back when I was an exchange student in
2013, I made my first ever video which
was pangok. It was just a way for me to
express the cultural differences I was
experiencing in a funny way. So it was
just such a fun process and the idea of
spending this amount of time to reach
potentially this amount of people, it
just went deep into my soul and it
became something like a dream. So I went
into finance, worked there for 3 years
in Hilton's finance team. Then I went
into a big blockchain company in Hong
Kong. And then that company essentially
asked me to quit. Whoops. [laughter] At
that point, I was thinking, look, I can
either go ahead and chase my dreams or
find another job. And this might be some
sort of sign from the universe. So I
said, screw it. Let's take a big risk.
Go to Korea. Let's make some content.
And here we are 6 years later, more than
2 million followers. Thank you
everybody. I love you so much.
>> He's got two silver buttons now.
>> Yeah.
>> That's crazy.
>> Give me a gold. Let's go. Let's get that
gold, baby.
>> Do you remember your first ever viral
video?
>> Oh, my first ever Tik Tok video went
viral. It's where I dressed up as a
woman and I was making a very terrible
dad joke. It was like
and then it's like
and that's it. That first video went
viral which I'm very grateful for
because that made me keep on making
content.
>> But I think the most viral series was my
series where people would challenge me
to do things and I went and made it look
easy.
>> What kind of challenges did you have to
do? Uh, I think it was everything from
like eating food, traveling around
different cities, and spending the whole
day there. But the most interesting ones
were probably me getting my wisdom tooth
removed. Oh, two of them actually. Or
>> you filmed that?
>> Yeah, I filmed that. Blood and
everything. Another interesting one, I
got my entire body lasered like head to
toe.
>> That was my follow-up question. I was
going to ask, what's the craziest thing
you've ever done for content?
>> Maybe. Actually, there was probably
something crazier. I was at Jejudor and
I was riding an electric bicycle and I
had an accident.
>> Okay.
>> And I broke my collarbone. So you can
actually see it here. The scar.
>> Yeah, there's the scar.
>> Yeah. And the entire process, I filmed
it all. That was a fun video. Yeah, that
was nice.
>> Wow.
>> So, as soon as I fell over, like first
thing I said to my friend was I can't
even breathe yet. Like, oh, get the
phone, start recording. I need content,
baby. Let's go. And that became a nice
viral banger as well.
>> Wow. You are a true content creator.
>> Yeah, it's fun. I love it. It's such an
amazing and fun world.
>> I've seen you do mukbangs. I've seen you
eat with strangers on the street,
interview people on the street, even go
into strangers homes and cook with them.
What is your favorite type of video that
you make?
>> I think back in the day when I still had
a lot of things to explore in the world,
Kumiji was great because it let me try
new things, new foods, new places. But
now these days I'm thinking what's one
thing that can't be replaced by AI and
that became street interviews. So I'm
really enjoying cuz I'm a super
extrovert. I love humans, you know.
>> Mhm.
>> So I use interviews as my way to combine
my true personality with also some form
of monetization and it's the perfect
combination.
>> That's great. I need some of that energy
cuz actually I'm an introvert.
>> You're an introvert?
>> Yeah.
>> You've got such energy though. What are
you talking about?
>> No way.
>> I am. I am. I took the test and I was
like 52.
>> Oh mate, [laughter] they need to have a
like a third symbol for like, you know,
half and half, right?
>> How do you approach people on the
street?
>> I just do it.
>> You just go for it.
>> I just go for it. I don't know how much
of my past I should reveal, but you
know, I was a bit of an outcast, but
also had very little social skills. So
back in the day, it became a bit of a
project of mine, largely through women,
I guess.
>> Approached lots of women and then I
found a lot of confidence in speaking to
people. So now I have essentially no
fear of social situations.
>> Learn by doing, right?
>> Yeah. Like other day I approached Pakun
as well. I jumped in there, got the
interview, got the views. Excellent. I
win.
>> That's incredible.
>> No fear of people. I love it.
>> Dang, that's a superpower.
>> Yeah, it's pretty useful. Yeah.
>> Have you ever been rejected?
>> All the time. Yeah, all the time getting
rejected. But I don't think rejections
are a negative thing. They're just part
of the process
>> and it can be enjoyable except when they
say things a bit harsh. Just move on.
You say, "Okay, next." And I can kind of
like scout it out now. I'm like, "This
person's going to recognize me." So, I
just go in and oh,
>> you see them kind of watching a little
bit or looking
>> even if they haven't seen me yet. I'm
like, "Ah, that's my demographic." And
you know, my demographic in Korea,
pretty solid saturation.
>> I went out with him in Busousan and
literally he was stopped every minute.
People were like, "Oh, I've seen your
videos. Oh, Chumbo." Like that was
pretty cool.
>> Thank you guys. Thank you for
recognizing.
>> Have you ever had like a weird fan?
>> Oh my god. Yes. There's two types of
people I just cannot tolerate. One is
the ones who kind of like grab you.
>> Physically grab you.
>> Yeah. Physically grab you. I don't like
getting touched by strangers. Like if
we're already in conversation, fine.
Like that's fine. But like if you come
up behind me and go like this, I'm like
bro. Like come on, bro. And then
there was one the other day, a very
distinct situation.
>> This guy comes up to me. He's like,
and then he gets his phone, shoves it in
my face this distance. He's like like
right now. And then he's like,
and then he went back. He was like,
>> and then he unfollowed me like in two in
two seconds.
>> He unfollowed you?
>> Yes. I was like, bro, like I don't even
know who the guy is. We had a nice
conversation and stuff. I can think
about it, but I don't know who the guy
is.
>> That's so savage. What the heck?
>> Yeah. Very strange.
>> Were you surprised when people first
started recognizing you?
>> Oh, yeah. It was crazy. It was like
biggest dopamine rush. I was just
walking to the convenience store and
somebody recognized me. I was like,
"Wo."
>> Mhm.
>> I've made it. I've done something. Like
the reality of a content creator, you're
just sitting in your bedroom most of the
time just sitting on your computer
editing videos. So, it's kind of
interesting that this very benign task
leads to so much happiness and
recognition from people. Like I I enjoy
making videos, but I don't quite
understand why people watch them
sometimes most of the time,
>> but they do and I'm so grateful for
that. So, thank you for enjoying my
videos, guys.
>> No, I think you have such a strong
presence and people can just see your
confidence in the videos and you always
keep things very fresh and new.
>> Like, I never know what's going to
happen in your videos. I love the way
you interact with people. Well, I mean,
lately you're making the videos where
you buy things for people, right? That
seems to be going well.
>> Yeah, it's going not bad. Like, uh, last
year during Christmas, I was out of
video ideas,
>> so I said, screw it. Let's put on a
Santa outfit and give out some gifts to
people. It went well, and I thought,
let's try this in normal clothing. It
went well, and thanks to that, you know,
I've collaborated with Mosins, Uniqlo, a
lot of big brands. It's It's kind of
wild, you know.
>> That's so true. That gives you like good
collab. Yeah, cuz you can insert any
sort of product into the video.
>> That's true.
>> So, advertisers, please reach out.
>> Do you use your own money?
>> All my own money. Yes.
>> Wow.
>> It's an investment I consider.
>> What's the most expensive thing someone
has asked for you to buy them?
>> Uh, two Labo perfumes. That was probably
like Guushi one or something.
>> Oo, okay.
>> But that was for an ad.
>> For a non ad video, the most expensive
thing I bought was probably a leather
jacket or something.
>> That's a nice gift. If I was out just
walking on the street and then got a
free leather jacket, I'd be happy.
>> Yeah. But I've noticed something with
Korean people in general.
>> If I did the exact same concept in the
States, I think that people would ask
for very big things.
>> And considering how much content
creators make in the States,
>> you'd be expected to provide those
things. But I've noticed that in Korea,
most people actually feel maybe a bit of
a burden to ask for something too big.
Mhm.
>> So, it's not as expensive as I expected
when I started the series.
>> I saw a lot of heartwarming videos where
they were just very excited to see you.
I think I saw one where you went out to
lunch or dinner with a kid.
>> Yeah, I like those.
>> Someone's day.
>> One time somebody bought me lunch and I
was like, "What the hell?" Thank you.
Like,
>> that's so sweet.
>> Amazing. Yeah.
>> So, you made it to the hold stage of
Hook Yodisa, right?
>> Yes, that is correct. So back then I was
making a lot of cooking content
>> and I applied for the show. I came up
with this immaculate tador bag and also
orange rice dish that is from my
background.
>> Oh, it's a Australian food.
>> No. Well, I'm Armenian, but my parents
were born in Iran.
>> So it's kind of a Persian dish.
>> So I I called my dishb. It was a
combination of my favorite slash my best
dish in Korean and the cooking that I
had at home in Australia. And I had a
bit of a screw- up because I had a very
specific meat supplier I needed to go
to, but they were closed by the time I
got there. So, I had to go to some
random meat shop and it was just
terrible quality. It was like full of
water. Just ruined my dish. It could
also just be me making excuses, but I
saw it was a really good pizza player.
And I got to the reserve stage, which
means I beat 60 professional chefs.
Let's go.
>> 60.
>> But you know, uh, we got edited out. So,
I was hoping for a bit of a more
explosive boost in fame, but that really
didn't come to fruition. So,
>> so they didn't show you on the show.
>> I was there for like 10 seconds. I had a
speaking line as well.
>> Oh, good.
>> I did enough. I've beat 60 people. I'm
good.
>> That's amazing.
How did you study Korean? How did your
Korean get so good? Uh so originally I
had four majors in university. So I did
finance, international business, Chinese
and Korean. And then when I came to
Korea as an exchange student at Soul
National, it wasn't the classes that
helped me learn Korean. It was me
getting out of the house, getting drunk
every single night and talking to
strangers. So I I knew nobody at all.
And I think that's why my speaking got
so good. I went outside convenience
stores. I would buy a bottle of soju. I
would chug it in one shot. A sort of
party trick. And then if anybody was
like, "Oh, wa." Then I'll be like, "Oh,
and just like hang out with them for the
night." And then I would learn lots and
lots of dialects and styles of speaking
very quickly because you get exposed to
different people.
>> Whereas I feel like when you meet people
who've only kind of like found one
partner, they start adapting that
person's speech patterns, which is not
wrong. It's fine. But I think that
really helped me get my speaking better.
>> No, it's good to learn different
accents, dialects, all that. It's very
helpful. Only downfall was since I
learned so much on the streets. I used
to swear a lot and speak very very
terrible like offensive Korean.
>> Mhm.
>> But I've gotten rid of most of it.
>> Okay.
>> But I'm still Australian, so swearing is
natural for me. So if anybody hears me
swearing on the streets, excuse me.
>> Do you find that when you're speaking in
a different language, your personality
changes a little bit? I personally don't
find it to change, but I get the
feedback very often that I'm a
completely different person in each
language.
>> Okay.
>> Apparently, I'm very sexy and charming
in English, but I sound like a child
when I speak in Korean. [laughter] Sexy
boy is English. Child is Korean.
Armenian or Chinese are probably
somewhere in between. Why is it that
when I speak Korean, I'm not sexy. Can
somebody explain this to me?
>> Try. Go ahead. Try.
Oh, I shouldn't do the tongue. She She
reacted. PD just like went,
>> "Oh, wait. Are those girls running over
here?"
>> Oh my gosh, it worked. It worked.
>> Oh my god.
>> Girls are running.
>> They love it. They love it.
>> I love that you just said that you would
go to the bar and drink and that's how
you practice Korean. I've interviewed
quite a few people now and a lot of them
say pretty much the same thing.
>> Just drink.
>> Well, drink and [laughter]
drink and talk to other people.
>> I think I've got some very specific
advice for Koreans. Koreans can be
perfectionists. So, until they're good
at something, they don't want to do it.
But language, you have to do it to get
good at it, right? You have to fail a
lot to get good at it. The way I enjoy
the failing process is to think of it as
an experiment or like a video game for
myself. So, I'm not there trying to
impress other people. I'm there just
trying to test myself and be like, "Oh,
I'm going to throw out this word and see
what the reaction is." And if I get the
reaction I want, I'm like, "Oh, so I
should keep saying it that way." Screw
the perfectionism. Spit it out. Meet
some random people and enjoy the
process.
>> I love the video game analogy. That's so
true. You're just trying to like level
up and if you make a mistake, you get
another life, you know?
>> Frankly, think of it in reverse. We
don't speak perfect Korean, but when you
hear us make mistakes, do you even care?
No. So guess what? As native English
speakers who've already heard every
single country's accents with people
from native to absolute beginner, we
don't care about your ability. So just
go out there, test it. Don't worry about
your accent. Pangimoon, like the head of
UN, he's got an accent and he's still
kicking ass. So you can do it, too. BTS,
they got accents. They're kicking ass.
You know, just get in there. Boom.
>> Go for it.
>> That's it.
>> Cheers.
>> I like that.
Tomato.
>> Tomato.
>> Aluminum.
>> Buoy.
>> What?
>> I don't even know what that is. What?
>> That thing out there.
>> A boy.
>> Boy. That's a boy. You're a boy.
>> I'm a man. [laughter]
>> Garage.
>> Water.
>> Yogurt.
>> Really? I thought it was yogurt.
>> What are you talking about? Where are
you getting your info from? [laughter]
>> McDonald's or Mickey De's?
>> McDonald's or Mackers?
>> Candy,
>> lollies,
>> shrimp,
>> prawns.
>> Chamombo, thank you so much for coming
today.
>> Thank you.
>> And guys, if you're not following him,
I'm sure you are, [music] but if you're
not, make sure to check him out and
follow him on what you've got
everything.
>> YouTube, Insta, Tik [music] Tok, search
Timbo, and look for me. Thank you for
watching. Thanks for having me on the
show.
All right, thank you for watching and we
will see you next time.